ALEXIS OVITT

UX/UI DESIGNER

About Me

I am empathetic, curious, and collaborative. I love giving and receiving feedback, and I am a capable storyteller and presenter. As a media producer -turned UX/UI Designer, I am adept at advocating for my products and for my users. On day one I will add value to your design team with my enthusiasm, logical mind, and passion for user-centered design.

Skills

- Research
- Interviewing
- Information Architecture
- User Journeys & Stories
- User Personas
- Affinity Mapping
- Flows & Mental Maps
- Red Routes
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- UI Design
- User Testing & Scripting
- Pattern Library
- Native & Responsive Design
- Design Language System
- Basic HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Tools

- Sketch
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Balsamiq
- 1 \ /: :
- InVision
- Proto.io
- Prott
- Axure
- KeynoteG Suite
- G Suite
- Codepen
- Slack
- GitHub
- Testing & Surveying Sites

Education

CAREER FOUNDRY / UX Design Certification

December 2018 - June 2019

- Over 300 hours of hands-on training focusing on data-driven UX methodology
- Closely mentored by a designer from Google

INDIANA UNIVERSITY / Masters Digital Media

August 2013 - May 2015

- Trained by veteran and award-winning Hollywood and PBS filmakers
- Led the post-production team for Academy Award nominated actor and director

University of New Mexico / B.A. American Studies

August 2007 - December 2011

- Dean's List
- Writing Tutor

Experience

Freelance / Digital Media Producer

October 2015 - Present

- Research, design and prototype mobile apps and responsive websites using software like Sketch, Balsamiq, Illustrator and InVision.
- Solve design challenges by conducting user interviews, surveys and affinity mapping, resulting in more customer-focused MVPs.
- Produce marketing and educational videos, and design logos and posters.

HERTZ / Assistant Manager

March 2017 - August 2018

- Created a QR coded survey which increased ease of use and in turn boosted customer survey engagement numbers.
- Managed rental logistics by carefully anticipating supply and demand, and moving fleet accordingly.
- Fulfilled customer needs and removed pain points through listening, empathizing, and advocating on their behalf.

KELLEY SCHOOL of BUSINESS / Video Marketer

November 2015 - November 2016

- Improved audience engagement by increasing post-production output, resulting in nearly 100k combined views in less than 1 year.
- Contributed to a rise in female, minority, and international undergraduate and MBA recruitment by advocating to elevate their voices in our videos.
- Presented & pitched to a variety of stakeholders, including the Dean.
- Upheld the professionalism and reliability of the Kelley brand while interviewing influential executives and alumni.

INDIANA UNIVERSITY / Assistant Instructor

August 2013 - November 2015

- Enhanced classroom experience by developing lesson plans and iterating according to peer, student, and professor feedback.
- Created a comprehensive post-production curriculum which was necessary to complete a large-scale multimedia project.
- Taught and mentored undergraduate students in the theoretical and practical areas of media creation.
- Received excellent evaluations from both faculty and students for my contributions to film projects, curriculum, and classroom engagement.

ZEICHNER RISK ANALYTICS / Communications Specialist

December 2010 - August 2013

- Translated complicated cybersecurity concepts into easily understood education materials.
- Collaborated with analysts, engineers, lawyers, and writers in the production of our e-learning initiative, culminating in an e-textbook.
- Managed a tight schedule for all digital deliverables in a fast-paced startup environment.